So beautiful.
好美
We're the same temperature now.
我们的体温相同了
Hey, Bella,
贝拉
you're a lot stronger than I am right now.
现在妳比我更强了
It's your turn not to break me.
换妳别弄伤我
I love you.
我爱你
Renesmee.
芮妮思蜜
She's incredible.
她很棒
Where is she? I have to see her.
她在哪里？我要看她
Wait. Wait.
等等，等等
You need to get your thirst under control.
妳需要先止渴
Yeah, you'll need to hunt.
妳需要狩猎
Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛
What do you hear?
妳听到什么？
Bella, don't!
贝拉，不要
Bella, stop!
贝拉，别过去
I'm sorry, I didn't realize there'd be people this far from the trails.
抱歉，没想到这么偏远会有人
I have to get outta here.
我要离开这里
Okay, I can help you.
我能帮妳
Or not.
不必了
Well, I'm amazed.
我很惊讶
You ran away from human blood mid-hunt.
妳在猎食时能放弃人血
Even mature vampires have problems with that.
连老经验的吸血鬼都很难做到
You're still here.
你还在
So are you.
妳也是
I didn't expect you to seem so
我没想到妳看起来还是......
you.
一样美
Except for the creepy eyes.
除了那双阴森的眼眸
I would keep my distance for now.
我们最好保持距离
It's safer for the baby to see how you do with me first.
先拿我当实验品对宝宝比较安全
Since when do you care about Renesmee?
你哪时关心起芮妮思蜜了？
All right.
好吧
Take a whiff.
闻我的味道
Well, I can see what everyone's been talking about.
我懂大家的意思了
Jake, you really do stink.
小各，你臭死了
You GUYS
你们俩......
really look great together.
看起来很登对
Want to come meet our daughter?
想见我们的女儿吗？
Welcome to the family.
欢迎回家
You look amazing, Bella.
妳气色真好
Someone's been waiting to meet you.
宝宝正等着见妳
Rose.
罗丝
Beautiful.
妳好美
What was that?
怎么回事？
She showed you the first memory she has of you.
她想表达对妳的第一印象
Showed me? How?
她怎么会表达？
How do I hear thoughts?
就像我能听见别人想法
How does Alice see the future?
艾利丝能预见未来
She's gifted.
她天赋异禀
I've only been out for two days?
我才昏迷两天？
Her growth rate is unprecedented.
她的成长速度前所未见
All right. That's enough experimenting for one day.
好了，今天试验够多了
Jacob.
雅各布布
She's doing great.
她克制得了
Yeah. Let's not push it though.
好，但别再冒险了
What's your problem?
你有什么问题？
Do tell her, Jacob.
告诉她
This should be good.
好戏来了
Hold on a second.
我抱一下
Bella.
贝拉
Look,
听着
it's a wolf thing.
狼人就这样
What's a wolf thing?
狼人就怎样？
You know we have no control over it.
妳懂我们控制不了
We can't choose who it happens with.
我们无法选择命定对象
And it doesn't mean what you think, Bella. I promise.
但别误会，我保证
Take Renesmee out of the room.
把芮妮思蜜抱出房间
Edward, don't touch me right now. I don't want to hurt you.
爱德华，别碰我，我不想伤到你
You imprinted on my daughter?
你命定我女儿？
It wasn't my choice!
我无从选择
She's a baby!
她还这么小
It's not like that.
别会错意
You think Edward would let me live if it was?
不然妳以为爱德华会留我活口？
I'm still debating it.
我仍在考虑
I've held her once!
我只抱过她一次
One time, Jacob!
才一次
And already you think that you have some moronic wolfy claim on her?
你就已经肖想对她伸出狼爪？
She's mine!
她是我的
It's fine, Leah.
没关系，利雅
You're gonna stay away from her.
不准你接近她
You know I can't do that.
我办不到
Stop her, Edward.
阻止她，爱德华
He said it's fine.
他说没关系
She's amazing, right?
她很厉害吧
Do you remember how much you wanted to be around me 3 days ago?
记得三天前妳多需要我陪伴吗？
That's gone now, right?
都过去了，对吧？
Long gone.
早就过去了
Because itwas her.
我是为了她
From the beginning it was Nessie who wanted me there.
从一开始就是妮思要我留下
Nessie?
妮思？
You nicknamed my daughter after the Loch Ness monster?
你昵称我女儿是尼斯水怪？
Seth, are you okay?
赛斯，没事吧？
Seth, I'm sorry.
赛斯，抱歉
He'll be all right.
他没事
Bella,
贝拉
you know me better than anyone.
妳比任何人都了解我
All I want is for Ness...
我只希望妮思…
Renesmee to be safe. Happy.
芮妮思蜜能够安全和快乐
Look,
听着
nothing ever made sense before.
之前的一切已是过眼烟云
You. Me. Any of it.
妳和我，任何过往
And now I understand why.
现在我了解原因了
This was the reason.
她就是理由
Finally.
终于
My turn.
换我了
Where does she sleep?
她睡哪里？
In my arms. Or Edward's or Esme's.
我怀里，或爱德华或艾思蜜怀里
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
I stopped aging three days ago.
我三天前就停止变老了
Well, we're celebrating anyway. So suck it up.
反正要庆祝，别抱怨了
I still hate surprises. That hasn't changed.
我还是讨厌惊喜，这点没变
You'll love this one.
这次可不同
Welcome home!
欢迎回家
We thought you guys might like a place of your own.
我们觉得妳可能想要自己的家
What do you think?
喜欢吗？
I think it's perfect.
太完美了
Go inside.
快进去
Have fun.
尽情享受
This will be Renesmee's room.
这是婴儿房
Closet.
衣橱
WOW.
好棒
Alice stocked it for you.
艾利丝替妳选的
Clearly.
看得出来
This is our room.
我们的房间
Vampires don't sleep.
吸血鬼又不睡觉
It's not intended for sleep.
这里不是用来睡觉的
You really were holding back before.
你以前太节制了
I'm never gonna get enough of this.
我会索求无度喔
We don't get tired.
我们不会累
We don't have to rest or catch our breath or eat.
我们不必休息、喘息、进食
I mean, I mean,
那么......
how are we gonna stop?
我们怎样才会停止爱爱？
Rosalie and Emmettwere so bad, it took a solid decade
罗丝莉和艾密特玩得很火
before we could stand to be within five miles of them.
缠绵了整整十年才见到人
I think we might be worse.
我们可能会玩得更火
Definitely worse.
那是当然的
EMMETTl WOW.
好快
Done already?
已经结束了？
Where's Renesmee?
芮妮思蜜在哪里？
Blondie stole her.
金发妞偷走她了
Break a lot of stuff?
家具全毁吗？
Emmett.
艾密特
No.
别亏了
Is that Charlie?
是查理吗？
He's been calling twice a day.
他一天打两次
He's in pretty rough shape.
他急坏了
Eventually, we'll have to tell him you didn't make it.
我们迟早要骗他妳死了
He needs to mourn, Bella.
他需要哀悼
Okay. We'll do it tomorrow.
好，明天再说
I'm gonna miss this place.
我们会想念这个地方
We'll come back. We always do.
我们会回来，向来如此
Wait.
等等
Nobody said anything about leaving.
没人要你们走
Once people believe Bella's dead, we can't risk anyone seeing her.
一旦宣布贝拉死了 就不能让她露面
So you just disappear?
所以妳就突然消失？
Jacob, we don't have another choice.
我们别无选择了
Hey.
嗨
You heard anything?
有消息吗？
Charlie,
查理
Bella is... Uh...
贝拉…
No, she's not.
不，她没死
No, no, no, I mean, she's fine. She's back home and
对，她很好，她回家了
she's feeling better.
她好转了
Why didn't you say so? That's great.
你怎么不早讲？太好了
Wait.
等等
There's something you need to see first.
你需要先看一样东西
I need to see Bella.
你需要看贝拉
Look,
听着
in order for Bella to get better, she had to
为了让贝拉复原，她必须......
change.
改变
What do you mean, "change"?
“改变”是什么意思？
Here goes nothing.
豁出去了
What the hell are you doing?
你到底要干嘛？
You don't live in the world you think you do.
你跟我们是不同世界的人
Jacob, put your clothes on.
雅各布布，穿上衣服
Now, this may seem strange.
这可能看起来很怪异
Really strange. But
怪到不行，可是…
stranger things happen every day.
世上无奇不有
Trust me.
相信我
Look, I solved a problem.
我解决问题了
You were leaving.
妳还要走？
What did you expect me to do?
妳指望我怎么做？
You don't realize the danger you've put him in.
你会害了查理
The Volturi will kill anyone who knows about us.
佛杜里会杀光知道我们的人
No, I didn't tell him about you. Just me.
我没说妳的事，只有我
I only said you were different.
我只说妳不同了
And that we have a niece who we adopted.
还有我们领养一个侄女
I mean, seriously, Jake, he's not just gonna let that go.
他不会这么好骗
Did you consider the physical pain he'll put Bella through?
你想过他会让贝拉多难受？
It'll be like sticking a white hot branding iron down her throat.
就像一块白热烙铁插进她喉咙
And that's assuming she can control her thirst.
要是她能控制饥渴
Look, Charlie's been in hell.
查理非常伤痛
And I know you'll be much happier with him in your life.
我知道妳有他会更快乐
Jacob, don't try and pretend you're doing this for anyone but yourself.
少虚情假意了，你只为了自己
Sorry you feel that way
抱歉惹你不快
because he'll be here in 1 0 minutes.
因为他十分钟后会来
What?
什么？
These will irritate your eyes at first.
刚戴时眼睛会酸痛
The main thing is not to move too fast.
重点是动作不能太快
Try taking a seat. Crossing your legs.
尽量坐着，双腿交叉
Maybe a tad slower. Hmm.
或许再慢一点
And blink at least three times a minute.
一分钟至.少眨眼三次
Good.
很好
For a cartoon character.
好像卡通人物
Hold your breath. it will help with the thirst.
屏息有助于抑制饥渴
Just don't forget to move your shoulders so it looks like you're breathing.
耸肩会看起来像在呼吸
And don't sit so straight.
别坐得那么僵硬
Humans don't do that.
人类不会那样
Okay. I got it.
好，我懂了
Move around, blink, slouch.
移动、眨眼、放松
Good luck.
祝好运
Hello, Charlie.
你好，查理
Where's Bella?
贝拉在哪里？
Bella.
贝拉
Hi, Dad.
嗨，爸
Are you okay?
妳没事吧？
Never better.
再好不过了
Healthy as a horse.
身子好得很
You don't turn into an animal, too, do you?
妳不会也变成动物吧？
She wishes she was that awesome.
她很羡慕我
Let's give them some privacy.
让他们独处吧
Uh, Jake said that this...
小各说......
This was necessary.
有必要改变
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
I really think it would be better...
我想最好......
I wanna knowwhat happened to you.
我想知道妳发生什么事
I can't tell you.
我不能告诉你
I think I deserve an explanation.
我值得一个解释
You do.
没错
But if you really need one, I can't stay here.
但讲了我就不能留在这里
Oh, come on! No!
别这样，不行
No more going away!
别再消声匿迹了
Dad, you're just gonna have to trust that for whatever reason,
爸，你必须相信无论如何......
I'm all right.
我很好
I'm more than all right.
我好极了
Can you live with that?
你能接受吗？
Can I live With that?
我能接受吗？
Well, I don't know, Bella.
我不确定
I mean, I just watched a kid I've known his entire life
我刚见到我看着长大的孩子
turn into a very large dog.
变成一只大狗
My daughter looks like my daughter.
我女儿看起来没变
But doesn't.
但她变了
Can you please just believe that I'll tell you anything that you need to know?
拜托你相信我能说的都说了
And I don't need to know this?
所以我都不必知道了？
No.
对
Really, you don't.
你不必知道
Well...
好吧
Not gonna lose you again.
我不想再失去妳了
I can't.
我做不到
Then you won't.
那你就不会
I promise.
我答应你
I missed you, Bells.
我很想妳
So much.
朝思暮想
I missed you, Dad.
我也想你，爸
Charlie.
查理
This is Renesmee.
这是芮妮思蜜
Your niece?
你们的侄女？
Our daughter.
我们的女儿
Right.
好
The adoption.
领养的
Renee-semee?
芮妮“啥米”？
She's got your eyes, Bella.
她的眼睛很像妳
Need to know, I guess.
我想这也该解释
Well clone, Bella.
干得好，贝拉
Never seen a newborn show that kind of restraint.
没看过新生表现得这么老神在在
I'm not sure she is a newborn.
她不算新生吸血鬼吧
She's so tame.
她太温和了
Emmett, don't antagonize her. She's the strongest one in the house.
别激她，她是全家最强的
Please.
少来了
Don't hurt yourself, Emmett.
别自找苦吃，艾密特
All right. On 3. 1бн 1...
数到3
Did you see that?
看到没？
Thank you.
谢谢各位
My time as a human was over.
我身为人类的日子结束了
But I never felt more alive.
但我第一次感到真正活着
I was born to be a vampire. I was born to be a vampire.
我注定成为吸血鬼
Everything was falling into place.
一切逐渐上轨道了
Even the Volturi seemed to accept my new status.
连佛杜里都似乎接受我的新身分
Though they'd want proof eventually.
虽然他们终究想要证据
It seemed we had only one enemy left.
我们似乎只剩一个敌人
Time.
时间
Renesmee was growing too fast.
芮妮思蜜长得太快了
We all worried about how long we would have with her.
我们都担心她能陪伴我们多久
It just made every moment more precious.
这使每一刻都更加珍贵
Look, a snowflake.
看，是雪花耶
It's beautiful.
好漂亮
Why don't you go get another one?
再去捡一些吧
Edward thinks that we'll find answers in Brazil.
爱德华认为在巴西能找到答案
There are tribes there that might know something.
那里的部落也许知道真相
RENESMEEl Who was that?
那是谁？
I think that's our cousin from Denali.
应该是德纳利的表亲
Irina!
艾琳娜！
Tanya convinced lrina to come reconcile with us.
谭雅说服艾琳娜来跟我们和解
It looks like she changed her mind.
看来她改变心意了
Seeing Jacob must have been too much for her.
她看到雅各布布一定很煎熬
Wish I could have just spoken to her.
真希望我能跟她谈谈
She's family. She'll come around.
她是一家人，她会回心转意
What a pleasant surprise.
稀客啊
What do you want?
有何贵干？
I have to report a crime.
我要密告一起罪行
The Cullens...
库伦家族......
They've done something terrible.
他们做了一件可怕的事
Allow me, my dear.
别介意，亲爱的
Oh, my-
天啊......
What is it, Alice?
怎么回事？
The Volturi.
佛杜里家族
They're coming for us.
他们找上门了
Aro, Caius, Marcus, the Guard.
厄洛、西泽、马库斯、侍卫
And lrina.
还有艾琳娜
Honey, come here.
女儿，过来
Why?
为什么？
What did lrina see in the woods?
艾琳娜在树林里看到什么？
We were just walking.
我们只是散步
Ness was catching snowflakes.
妮思在捡雪花
Of course.
我明白了
Irina thinks Renesmee's an lmmortal Child.
艾琳娜以为芮妮思蜜是不朽孩童
The lmmortal Children were very beautiful.
不朽孩童很美丽
So enchanting.
很迷人
To be near them was to love them.
接近就会爱上他们
But their development was frozen at the age they were turned.
但他们被咬后就停止发育
They couldn't be taught or restrained.
变得不受教又不自制
A single tantrum could destroy an entire village.
一发怒就会毁掉整个村落
Humans heard about the devastation.
人类听说这种毁灭
Stories spread.
故事流传
The Volturi were forced to intervene.
佛杜里不得不干预
Since the Children couldn't protect our secret,
因为不朽孩童会曝露我们的秘密
they had to be destroyed.
他们必须被摧毁
No!
不！
Their creators grew very attached and fought to protect them.
创造他们的人会变得放不下 拼命保护他们
Long-established covens were torn apart.
由来已久的吸血鬼族就会分裂
Countless humans slaughtered.
无数的人类会遭残杀
Traditions, friends,
传统、盟友
even families. Lost.
甚至家族都会灭绝
No, no!
不
- Mother! - No!
妈！
So the Denalis' mother made an lmmortal Child?
德纳利的母亲创造不朽孩童？
Yes.
对
And she paid the price.
她付出代价了
Well, Renesmee's nothing like those children.
芮妮思蜜才不是不朽孩童
She was born, not bitten. She grows every single day.
她是出生，不是被咬 她每天不断长大
So can't you just explain that to the Volturi?
你们不能跟佛杜里解释吗？
Aro has enough proof in lrina's thoughts.
艾琳娜的记忆让厄洛有足够证据
So we fight.
那我们就迎战
Their offensive weapons are too powerful.
他们的武力太强大了
No one can stand against Jane.
没人敌得过珍
Alec's even worse.
亚力克更可怕
Well, then we convince them.
那我们说服他们
They're coming to kill us, not to talk.
他们是来杀我们，不是来谈判
No, you're right.
你说的对
They won't listen to us.
他们不会听我们的
But maybe others can convince them.
但或许其它人能说服他们
Carlisle, you have friends all around the world.
卡莱尔，你的朋友遍布全世界
I won't ask them to fight.
我不会要求他们作战
Not fight. Witness.
不是作战，是作证
If enough people knew the truth,
如果够多人知道真相
maybe we could convince the Volturi to listen.
或许就能说服佛杜里聆听
We can ask this of our friends.
我们能请求朋友作证
At least we get to go to London again. At least we get to go to London again.
起码能重游伦敦
We haven't been there in a long time.
我们很久没去了
All right. Let's get this show on the road.
好，展开行动吧
Alice asked me to give you that.
艾利丝要我把信交给你
She and Jasper crossed our lands to the ocean last night.
她和贾斯柏昨晚越过狼人区去沿海
Carlisle?
卡莱尔？
They've left us.
他们离开我们了
Why?
为什么？
She didn't say.
她没说
Can I see that?
我能看吗？
Gather as many witnesses as you can before the snow sticks to the ground.
积雪前召集最多的证人
That's when they'll come.
到时佛杜里就会来临
Alice's instructions were clear, but the question remained.
艾利丝的指示很清楚但问题仍在
Why would she and Jasper leave at the moment we needed them most?
为何他们在我们最无助时离开？
What did they know?
他们知道什么？
Our search for witnesses began with a trip north to our closest relatives.
我们追寻证人始于北方的至亲
Edward, is everything all right?
爱德华，一切安好？
Why didn't you tell us you were coming?
怎么没说你会来？
Is it lrina?
因为艾琳娜吗？
Have you heard from her?
有她的消息吗？
Not directly.
间接听到
Why is your bride waiting in the car?
为什么你的新娘在车上等？
And why have you brought a wolf with you?
还有你怎么带来一个狼人？
I can smell him from here.
我在这里就闻到他了
My family is in danger. I need your help.
我的家族有危险，需要你们帮助
What's happened?
发生什么事？
It's hard to explain
很难解释
but I need you to be open-minded. Can you do that?
你们要抛开成见，可以吗？
Of course.
当然了
Okay.
好了
Time to meet some new people.
该去见新朋友了
What if they don't like me?
要是他们不喜欢我呢？
- They'll love you. -They will.
他们会喜欢妳的 一定会
Once they understand you.
只要他们了解妳
They just haven't met anyone like you before.
他们只是没遇过像妳一样的人
Okay.
好
The Volturi will come for all of us.
佛杜里会找上我们所有人
You get that thing out of here.
把那怪物带走
She's not what she looks like.
她不是不朽孩童
This is a crime!
这是罪行！
Stay back!
别靠近
She has blood in her veins.
她的身体流着人血
You can feel her warmth.
你们能感觉到她的体温
I can feel it.
我感觉到了
I'm her biological father.
我是她的生父
- Bella is her mother. -lmpossible.
贝拉是她的生母 不可能
It's true. She was born while I was still human.
是真的 她出生时我还是人类
I've never heard of such a thing.
我从没听过这种事
She can show you, if you let her.
她能证明给你们看
Tanya, you owe us this much.
谭雅，妳欠我们这个人情
We're all under a death sentence because your sister didn't let us explain.
我们被判死就是因为… 妳妹不让我们解释
Don't be afraid.
别害怕
This is how she communicates.
这是她的沟通方式
It's true.
是真的
She's not immortal.
她不是不朽孩童
I knew the rest of our family would face this fear as well.
我的家人将要面对这种恐惧
Fear of the unknown.
未知的恐惧
Fear of the Volturi.
对佛杜里的恐惧
Amun, please!
阿穆，拜托
I cannot help you, Carlisle.
我帮不了你
I wouldn't ask if it weren't urgent.
情况危急我才求你
You must go.
你们该走了
I'd like to hear about it.
我倒想听听
I never get to meet any of Amun's friends.
我没见过阿穆的任何朋友
He likes to keep me hidden.
他老爱把我藏起来
I can't imagine why.
真想不通啊
- Carlisle.
卡莱尔
-Benjamin.
班杰明
Benjamin can influence the elements.
班杰明能影响五行
And here I get super self-control.
那我是自制力过人
Who are they?
她们是谁？
Senna and Zafrina.
辛娜和莎菲娜
From the Amazon.
来自亚马孙河
The arrival of Senna and Zafrina meant that our plea was being heard
这表示我们的恳求…
in even the most remote corners of the world
连天涯海角都被听到了
while others searched for witnesses closer to home.
其它人正在寻找国内的证人
A patriot Carlisle first met on the battlefield at Yorktown
卡莱尔当初在约克镇战场 遇到的一名爱国者
would become our most unlikely ally.
成为我们最讶异的同盟
Shut up!
闭嘴
I hated the first British lnvasion.
我痛恨第一次英国入侵
And I hate the second one even more.
更痛恨第二次
Even the Beatles?
连披头四也讨厌？
Really, Garrett?
不会吧，嘉瑞特
Old habits die hard.
本性难移
Carlisle needs you.
卡莱尔需要你
Sounds interesting.
这可有趣了
Help!
救命！
But first I'd better finish my meal.
但先让我嗑完这一餐
Help me! Help!
救我！救命！
Each of them was won over.
每个人都被说动
Each was made to see.
每个人都了然于心
Carlisle convinced his lrish friends to make the journey to Forks.
卡莱尔说服他的爱尔兰朋友 前来福克斯
Although we were grateful for their help,
虽然我们很感谢他们
their thirst for human blood complicated the situation.
他们对人血的渴望使情况变复杂
The nomads Rosalie and Emmett sent were even more unpredictable.
罗丝莉和艾密特找来的流浪吸血鬼 更是不可预测
Especially Peter
尤其是彼得
who had fought alongside Jasper as a newborn.
他新生时是贾斯柏的战友
Lotta red eyes around here.
这里变成吸血鬼大本营
They agreed not to hunt in the area.
他们同意不在这一区狩猎
But they'll feed somewhere.
但他们会在别处猎食
As more vampires set foot in their territory,
随着愈多吸血鬼侵入狼人领地
more Quileutes turned.
愈多奎鲁特族变身
Their nature compelling them to join the pack.
他们出于天性变成狼人
Hey, easy there. Hey!
别激动 冷静
it's all right.
不要紧
You're gonna be okay.
你会没事的
Finally, Carlisle and Esme returned with our last witness.
终于卡莱尔和艾思蜜带回最后证人
- How many came? - Eighteen.
来了多.少人？ 18人
You have some good friends.
你有不.少忠实朋友
And Alice?
艾利丝呢？
We'll all be on Aro's list now.
我们都成为厄洛的黑名单
Centuries on the run. That's what you've brought me.
我逃亡了几世纪都是被你害的
Some friend, Carlisle.
交友不慎啊，卡莱尔
Alistair, come meet everyone.
艾利斯泰，来见见大家
I already told you, if it comes to a fight, I won't stand against the Volturi.
我早说了 如果酿成战争，我打不过佛杜里
It won't come to a fight.
才不会酿成战争
I'll be in the attic.
我要去阁楼了
He's not a people person.
他不善交际
We opened our home to 1 8 vampires.
我们邀来18个吸血鬼
Many with gifts of their own.
许多有独自的天赋
Zafrina had power over the mind.
莎菲娜能蛊惑人心
She could make anyone see what she wanted them to.
她能使任何人产生幻觉
If she weren't holding my hand right now, I could swear this was real.
要不是妳牵我的手 我会发誓这是真的
I don't see anything.
我什么也没看到
Edward, you didn't tell me your wife is a shield.
爱德华，你没说你老婆是保护罩
What's a shield?
什么是保护罩？
The ones I've met are so different.
我遇过的保护罩跟她不同
It's a defensive talent.
是防御的技能
It's why I couldn't read your mind, even before.
所以我连之前都读不到妳的想法
It's why Aro couldn't.
厄洛也不能
You have a very powerful gift.
妳有很强大的天赋
Oh, yeah, she's a shield, all right.
她果然是保护罩
Shoulda put her on her ass.
难怪她没跌个四脚朝天
Or your voltage has been exaggerated.
或者妳的电压被高估了
Maybe it only works on the weak.
或许只对弱者管用
Garrett, I wouldn't.
嘉瑞特，别招惹她
You are an amazing woman.
妳......电死我了
Now, you guys can do some serious damage.
你们能造成严重的损害
Which is why you'll need to control your phasing.
所以你们要控制变身
If your mom pisses you off,
如果你老妈激怒你
you don't want to tear her head off.
你可不想扭断她的头
Whoever's coming wasn't invited.
来者不善
Vladimir, Stefan,
弗拉德，斯提凡
you're a long way from home.
你们远道而来
What are they doing here?
他们来这里干嘛？
We heard the Volturi were moving against you.
我们听说佛杜里要制裁你们
But that you would not stand alone.
但你们不会孤军奋战
We didn't do what we were accused of.
我们受到诬告
We do not care what you did, Carlisle.
我们不在乎你们的所作所为
We have been waiting a millennium
我们等了一千年
for the ltalian scum to be challenged.
就为了挑战那些意大利人渣
It's not our plan to fight the Volturi.
我们的计划不是跟佛杜里作战
Shame.
太可惜了
Aro's witnesses will be so disappointed.
厄洛的证人会失望透顶
They enjoy a good fight.
他们喜欢一场好战
Aro's witnesses?
厄洛的证人？
Still hoping they'll listen?
仍希望他们会聆听？
When Aro wants someone from a coven
当厄洛想占有某个吸血鬼
it's never long before evidence turns up proving that coven committed some crime.
不久就会出现… 显示那个吸血鬼犯罪的证据
So he's done this before?
所以他有过先例？
It happens so rarely, I never realized it was a pattern.
难得一见，我想不是常态
Apparently he always pardons one person whose thoughts he claims are repentant.
显然他向来会饶恕… 他认为有悔意的人
This person always has an ability.
这个人往往具有能力
And they're always given a place with the Guard.
总是会被赋予侍卫的地位
This is all about Alice.
关键就是艾利丝
- He has no one like her. -Which is why she left.
他手下没有像她的人 所以她才离开
Why does he need witnesses?
他为什么需要证人？
To spread the word that justice has been served.
在全世界散布正义已伸张
After he slaughters an entire coven.
在他杀光吸血鬼族之后
Benjamin, Tia,
班杰明，提雅
-we're leaving. -And where will you go?
我们要走了 你们要去哪里？
What makes you think they'll be satisfied with Alice?
你以为他们有艾利丝就会满意？
What's to stop them from going after Benjamin next?
谁能阻止他们下一个找上班杰明
Or Zafrina or Kate
或莎菲娜、凯特或任何有天赋的人
or anyone else with a gift? Anyone they want.
他们不会罢手
Their goal isn't punishment, it's power.
他们的目标不是惩罚
It's acquisition.
是权力，是并吞
Carlisle might not ask you to fight, but I will.
卡莱尔不会要求你们作战，但我会
For the sake of my family. But also for yours.
为了我的家族，也为了你们的
And for the way you want to live.
还有为了你们想要的生活
The packs will fight.
狼族会作战
We've never been afraid of vampires.
我们从不畏惧吸血鬼
We Will fight.
我们会作战
This won't be the first time I fought a king's rule.
这不是我第一次对抗君王统治
We'll join you.
我会加入你们
No.
不行
I will do the right thing, Amun.
我会做出正确抉择
You may do as you please.
加不加入随你
We will stand with you.
我们会跟你们同一阵线
So will we.
我们也是
That didn't take much.
大家真好说话
Let's hope it doesn't come to that.
希望不会挑起战火
We'll see.
等着看吧
Everyone showed courage.
每个人都表现出勇气
Though we knew that Aro's army was moving against us.
即使明知厄洛的军队要对付我们
Soon we would face the dark gifts of Jane.
很快我们会面对珍的残酷天赋
And worse, the paralyzing vapor of her brother Alec
更糟的是，她的兄弟亚力克
who could rob you of sight, sound and touch.
能剥夺五官触觉的麻痹天赋
I refused him!
我拒绝他
Alec?
亚力克
I will never go against you.
我绝对不会违背你
Of course not,
当然不会
my dear Toshiro.
我亲爱的敏郎
It seems Carlisle is still expecting you.
看来卡莱尔仍在期盼你
Carlisle is all but ensuring his own destruction.
卡莱尔必然会自寻死路
Sad,
可悲
isn't it?
不是吗？
Aro will want us incapacitated before he attacks.
厄洛在攻势前会削弱我们的势力
Jane and Alec will try and take me out first because I can anticipate their moves.
珍和亚力克会先设法除掉我 因为我能预测他们的行动
Too bad we don't all have your shield.
可惜我们没妳的保护罩
Doesn't help me fight, though.
那帮不了我作战
No, but you could help the rest of us,
不，只要妳能投射保护罩
if you could project it.
就能帮我们
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I mean shield someone other than yourself.
就是保护自己以外的人
Is that possible?
有可能吗？
Gifts can be developed. Over time.
天赋随时间增长
At first, mine was just in my palms.
一开始我只有手掌有电
Now I can radiate it all over my body.
现在我全身都能通电
How do you do it?
妳怎么做到的？
- Tell me. -Ow.
教我 好痛
You need to visualize it.
妳需要想象力
See how it moves.
看见它怎么移动
What color it is.
什么颜色
Now picture it expanding.
现在想象它扩大
Will it to go beyond you.
用意志力延伸它
I think she needs something to motivate her.
我想她需要某种动力
- No. -it's all right, I can take it.
不要 没关系，我能承受
He says that now.
话别说得太早
Focus, Bella, or he's gonna be hurting.
专心，贝拉，否则他会受伤
Edward, I'm not ready to do this yet.
我还没准备好
I'm sorry. I said that I wasn't ready.
抱歉，我就说没准备好
Dude, you're not motivating her.
老弟，你罩不住啦
You want to try?
换你试试？
Kate!
凯特
You seem to lack incentive.
妳似乎缺乏诱因
Shall I go see if Renesmee's awake?
去看看芮妮思蜜醒了没
Are you crazy?
妳疯了吗？
All right.
好吧
This one's on full power.
接着要使出全力了
It's painful, but it's bearable.
很痛但能忍受
Okay, we should go again.
再来一次
Emmett.
艾密特
I'm good.
我就免了
"There's sweet music here that..."
传来美妙的音乐
"softer falls than petals from blown roses on the grass."
比玫瑰花瓣吹落在草地轻柔
"Or night dews on still waters between walls..."
也比晚露滴落在墙间静水轻柔
"of shadowy granite in a gleaming pass."
周围是幽暗花岗岩的蒙眬通道
"Music that brings sweet sleep down from the blissful skies."
音乐从极乐天空带来香甜好梦
Mom.
妈
Did Aunt Alice and Uncle Jasper run away
艾利丝姑姑和贾斯柏叔叔走掉
because we're gonna die?
是因为我们会死吗？
No.
不是
I think they left to keep us safer.
他们离开是想让我们更安全
That's what all these other people are here for, too.
来这里的所有人也是
I'll never let anybody hurt you.
我绝不会让任何人伤害妳
Come here. Go to sleep.
过来，睡吧
It's strange.
好奇怪
Physically, I feel like I could demolish a tank.
身体上，我感觉能摧毁坦克
Mentally, I just feel drained.
精神上，却感觉一切耗尽
How about a bath?
泡个澡呢？
I do remember how to undress myself.
我还记得怎么脱衣服
Yeah, I just do it so much better.
这我比妳在行
Bella,
贝拉
I've had a bad habit of underestimating you.
我有低估妳的坏习惯
Every obstacle you've faced,
妳面对的每个难关
I'd think you couldn't overcome it.
我都以为妳熬不过
And you just did.
但妳都克服了
You're the reason they have something to fight for.
妳是他们战斗的信念
My family.
为了家人
I'm gonna get the water running.
我来放水
Alice made sure only I would get the message.
艾利丝确保只让我知道
Because only my mind would be safe from Aro.
因为厄洛读不到我心思
I'm surprised you took a break from Jedi training.
妳的绝地武士训练竟然能告假
If I don't take Renesmee to my dad, he'll come to us.
如果不把芮妮思蜜带给我爸 他就会找上我们
27 vampires, one human.
27个吸血鬼，1个人类
Not so great.
不太妙
I know that's what you told Edward.
妳也用这借口呼咙爱德华吧
Whatever.
无所谓
I'm just glad to get away from all those reeking bloodsuckers.
真高兴能摆脱那群发臭的吸血鬼
I'm sorry.
抱歉啦
I know.
我懂
They're the good guys.
他们是好人
But come on,
但说真的
Dracula One and Two are
德古拉一号和二号…
creepy.
超毛的
There she is. Come here. Oh!
她来了，过来
Wow! Look at you.
瞧妳
You've grown half a foot!
长大好多
Seriously.
不夸张
Like 6 inches.
少说有15公分
Come on inside. Lunch is on the table.
进来，午餐好了
We got a tree to decorate, huh?
我们要布置圣诞树
I've actually got a few errands to run, guys.
我要去办一些事
I'll be back soon, okay?
很快回来，好吗？
Come on. Let's go.
来吧，要开动了
Alice's note gave me a new sense of hope.
艾利丝的信给我新的希望
Maybe she had a plan for us after all.
或许她毕竟替我们想好计划
And maybe J. Jenks was the key.
也许甄克斯是关键
I'm meeting Mr. Jenks. Right this way.
我想见甄克斯先生 这边请
-Mrs. Cullen. -Hi.
库伦太太 你好
I'm so happy you called.
很高兴妳打来
I always meet my private clients here.
我都在这里见私人客户
It's more comfortable than the office.
比办公室更自在
And it's more public.
也更公开
Ah. What type of work do you do, J.?
你从事哪一行？
Oh, you know, this and that.
应有尽有
It's always different, which keeps it interesting.
随时变化，这样才有趣
Have you known Alice and Jasper long?
你认识艾利丝和贾斯柏很久吗？
I've been working with them for more than 20 years.
我跟他们合作超过20年了
And my late partner knew Jasper 1 5 years before that.
我过世的伙伴之前认识贾斯柏15年
He is, uh,
他......
unusually well-preserved.
保养功夫非比寻常
Yes, he is.
是啊
I trust that Mr. Jasper is enjoying his vacation.
我想贾斯柏先生正在渡假
He didn't tell you where he was going, did he?
他没告诉你要去哪里，是吗？
No,no,no, he just mentioned that he was leaving
没有，他过来下订时
when he came by to place his order.
只提到他要离开
I assume that his order is ready?
我猜他的订单准备好了？
Of course.
当然
I've never been late with a delivery.
我交货从不延误
There a problem?
有问题吗？
No.
没有
My husband and I thought that we'd all be traveling together.
我和外子以为我们会同行
Jasper said only two were traveling.
贾斯柏说是两人行
His instructions were very clear.
他的指示很清楚
It's my mistake.
是我弄错了
Apparently, that's not going to happen.
显然不可能如愿了
Alice's vision was clear.
艾利丝的预见很清楚
Renesmee would have a future.
芮妮思蜜会有未来
But Edward and I wouldn't be a pan' of it.
但我和爱德华不能陪她
How ya doin'?
妳好吗？
"My dearest Renesmee..."
我亲爱的芮妮思蜜
"l thought we would have forever together."
我以为我们会永远在一起
"But forever isn't as long as I 'd hoped."
但永远不如我期望的长久
"l know now why Alice left me clues."
我想通为何艾利丝会留给我线索
"ltwas to keep you safe."
是为了让妳安全
"Everything you and Jacob will need is in this pack."
妳和雅各布布需要的用品全在这背包里
"Jacob will protect you."
雅各布布会保护妳
"And he'll help you learn about the Ticuna legends."
他会教妳提卡纳族的传说
It's a romantic notion, isn't it?
这只是浪漫念头吧？
That a righteous few can defy a great evil.
少数良知能抵抗超级恶人
I must admit, you even had me believing.
我承认妳连我都说服了
For a moment.
暂时说服
Well, good luck. You're gonna need it.
祝好运，妳需要运气
Cheers.
再会
The snow is sticking.
积雪了
Hey, we still have today.
我们还有一天
I'm so glad Charlie found somebody to take care of him.
很高兴查理找到人照顾他
Bella, no one's giving up here.
没人会放弃的
All right! Present time! Let's go!
拆礼物时间，来吧
Seth, Leah, stop eating.
赛斯，利雅，别吃了
Jake, you start. Get it going.
小各，从你开始吧
What did you get me? I'm not giving you anything.
妳要送我什么？ 别作梦了
Hey! No, come on, what did you get me?
快点，妳要送我什么？
Well, Dad, we didn't have time to wrap yours, but here it is.
爸，我们没空包装，但这送你
It's a 5-day fishing trip to Fraser River.
是去弗雷泽河的五天钓鱼之旅
It's for you and Sue.
给你和苏
You leave tomorrow.
你们明天出发
Wow, that's really nice. Thank you.
真贴心，谢谢
Tomorrow?. I can't leave tomorrow.
但我明天走不了
I made arrangements for you at work.
我替你请好假了
Sneaky.
好贼
And extravagant.
也很奢侈
And non-refundable, I'm afraid.
恐怕不能退喔
You two trying to get rid of me?
你们是想支开我吗？
Because it's working!
果真奏效了
Fraser River. That means we'll be chasing Cutthroat.
弗雷泽河，那我们要钓割喉鳟
We might even hook a Rainbow or some Bulls.
也能钓虹鳟或牛鳟
Woman knows her trout.
她是鳟鱼专家呢
Hey, beautiful. Let me see.
小乖，让我看
Jacob make this for you?
雅各布布做给妳的吗？
Wanna put it on?
要戴上吗？
It's so pretty.
好漂亮
It is really pretty.
漂亮极了
That's what I'm talkin' about.
这样才象话
A little pre-battle bonfire.
点起战前营火
Telling war stories.
述说战争故事
Or just standing there like frickin' statues.
或是杵着像吓人雕像
Name any American battle. I was there.
列举任何美国战役，我都在场
Little Bighorn.
小大角之战
I came this close to biting Custer.
我差点就咬到卡斯特将军
But the lndians got him first.
但印地安人先杀掉他了
Try Oleg's assault on Constantinople.
想想欧格攻击康士坦汀普
He didn'twin that one on his own.
他不是独力打了胜战
If you're talking battles, you're talking the Eleven Years' War.
谈到战争.少不了十一年战争
No one does rebellion like the lrish.
没人比爱尔人擅长叛乱
You lost the Eleven Years' War.
你们输了十一年战争
Aye. But it was one hell of a rebellion.
对，但那次叛乱不是盖的
When we ruled, everything came to us.
我们统治时，一切都隶属我们
P FEY,
猎物
diplomats,
外交官
favor seekers.
政客
Such was our power.
当时我们的力量强大
But we never put on white hats and called ourselves saints.
但我们从未脸上贴金自称圣人
We were honest about what we were.
我们诚实接受自己的本质
We sat still for a very long time.
我们蛰伏着 很长一段时间
We didn't notice we were beginning to petrify.
没注意到我们开始僵化
Perhaps the Volturi did us a favor when they
或许佛杜里烧毁我们的城堡
burned our castles.
是帮我们一个大忙
We've been waiting 1,500 years
我们等待了1500年
to return that favor.
要回报这份人情
We have been ready to do battle for ages.
我们老早就准备好作战
I can't help thinking,
我不禁想到
all these people are putting themselves in danger
这些人投身于危险
because I fell in love with a human.
全因为我爱上人类
You found your mate.
你找到你的伴侣
You deserve to be happy.
你值得幸福
But atwhat cost?
但代价呢？
Everyone here has something to fight for.
这里的每个人都有战斗的理由
I certainly do.
我当然也有
Carlisle, I've never thanked you.
我从没向你道谢
For this extraordinary life.
给我不同凡响的人生
This means "More than my own life."
意思是“比我的生命宝贵”
That's how much I love you.
我就是这么爱妳
Tomorrow I'm gonna need you to stay with Jacob.
明天我要妳跟着雅各布布
No matterwhat.
无论如何
Even if I tell him that...
就算我要他…
That he has to take you somewhere.
带妳到别的地方
Hey.
别哭
Baby, it's all right.
宝贝，别怕
You're gonna be safe.
妳会很安全
Always.
永远都会
If we live through this,
要是这次幸存
I'll follow you anywhere, woman.
我会跟妳到天涯海角
Now you tell me.
现在才说
The Redcoats are coming! The Redcoats are coming!
敌军来了，敌军来了
Aro's looking for Alice.
厄洛在找艾利丝
Aro,
厄洛
Iet us discuss things as we used to.
让我们如往常讨论事情
In a civilized manner.
以文明的方式
Fairwords, Carlisle.
很有诚意，卡莱尔
But a little out of place,
但有点尴尬
given the battalion you've assembled against us.
显然你集结了对抗我们的大军
I can promise you, thatwas never my intent.
我能向你保证 这绝非我的本意
No laws have been broken.
我们没有犯法
We see the child.
我们看到那个孩子
Do not treat us as fools.
别把我们当傻子
She is not an lmmortal!
她不是不朽孩童
These witnesses can attest to that.
这群证人可以作证
Or you can look.
如你所见
See the flush of human blood in her cheeks.
她的脸颊有血色
Artifice!
诡计
I will collect every facet of the truth.
我会收集各方的真相
But from someone more central to the story.
但我想问一位当事人
Edward,
爱德华
as the child clings to your newborn mate,
这孩子属于你的新生伴侣
I assume you are involved.
想必你脱不了关系
I'd like to meet her.
我想要见她
Young Bella.
稚嫩的贝拉
Immortality becomes you.
不朽很适合妳
I hear her strange heart.
我听到她的奇怪心跳
Hello, Aro.
你好，厄洛
Magnifico!
太神奇了
Half mortal,
一半凡人
half immortal.
一半不朽
Conceived and carried by this
生母是这个…
newborn
新生
while she was still human.
在她还是人类时
Impossible!
不可能
Do you think they fooled me, brother?
兄弟，你当他们在愚弄我吗？
Bring the informer forward.
把密告者带上来
Is that the child you saw?
那是妳看到的孩子吗？
I'm not sure.
我不确定
Jane.
珍
She's changed. This child is bigger.
她变了 这个孩子比较大
Then your allegations were false.
那妳的主张是错的
The Cullens are innocent.
库伦家族是无辜的
I take full responsibility for my mistake.
我对我的过失负全责
I'm sorry.
对不起
Caius, no!
西泽，不要
Irina!
艾琳娜！
Blind them.
让她们看不见
Give me my sight back.
还我视力
Tanya, this is what they want.
别让他们得逞
If you attack now, we'll all die.
妳一攻击我们都会死
Pain.
痛苦
It's working.
成功了
Aro, you see there's no law broken here.
厄洛，这里没人犯法
Agreed.
同意
But does it then follow
但这就表示…
that there is no danger?
没危险吗？
For the first time in our history
我们吸血鬼史上头一遭
humans pose a threat
人类对我们族类
to our kind.
构成威胁
Their modern technology
人类的现代科技
has given birth to weapons that could destroy us.
诞生能毁灭我们的武器
Maintaining our secret
捍卫我们的秘密
has never been more imperative.
从未如此急迫
In such perilous times,
在这种危险时刻
only the known
唯有已知的事
is safe.
才是安全的
is tolerable.
才是容许的
And we know nothing
但我们对这孩子的未来
of what this child will become.
一无所知
Can we live with such uncertainty?
我们能接受这种不确定性吗？
Spare ourselves a fight today,
今天省去一场战斗
only to die
明天唯有…
tomorrow.
死路一条
No.
完了
Alice.
艾利丝
My dear, dear Alice,
我亲爱的艾利丝
we're so glad to see you here, after all.
很高兴终究见到妳了
I have evidence the child won't be a risk to our kind.
我能证实这孩子对我们族类无害
Let me show you.
我证明给你看
Brother?
兄弟？
it doesn't matter what I show you.
我怎么证明都没用
Even when you see.
就算你心知肚明
You still won't change your decision.
你仍然不会改变心意
Now!
开战
Take care of my daughter.
照顾我女儿
Get them.
去追他们
Take her away.
把她带走
Let her go!
放她走！
Jacob!
雅各布布！
Watch out!
小心！
Bella!
贝拉！
Finally.
终于
Now you know.
现在你明白了
That's your future.
那是你的未来
Unless you decide on another course.
除非你决定别的途径
We cannot alter our course. The child still poses a grave threat.
我们不能改变途径 这孩子仍是重大威胁
But what if you were sure she could remain concealed from the human world?
若能保证她不被人类知道？
Could we leave in peace?
能握手言和吗？
Of course. But that cannot be known.
当然，但那是未知数
Actually, it can.
并非如此
I've been searching for witnesses of my own
我亲自搜寻证人
among the Ticuna tribes of Brazil.
深入巴西的提卡纳族
- We have enough witnesses. -Let him speak, brother.
- 我们有证据 - 让他说
I am half human,
我是半人类
halfvampire.
半吸血鬼
Like the Child.
跟这孩子一样
A vampire seduced my mother,
有个吸血鬼诱惑我母亲
who died giving birth to me.
她死于难产
My aunt Huilen
我的阿姨胡兰
raised me as her own.
一手把我养大
I made her immortal.
我使她变吸血鬼
How old are you?
你几岁了？
150 years.
150岁
At what age did you reach maturity?
你几岁长大成人？
I became full-grown seven years after my birth.
我出生后7年长为成人
I have not changed since then.
从此就没改变
And your diet?
你的饮食呢？
Blood,
血
human food.
人类食物
I can survive on either.
两者皆可
These children are much like us.
这些孩子跟我们没两样
Regardless, the Cullens have been consorting with werewolves.
可是库伦家族与狼族结交
Our natural enemies.
我们的天敌
Dear ones,
同伴们
there is no danger here.
这里没有危险
We will not fight
我们今天不会…
today.
交战
Such a prize.
皆大欢喜
We have them on the run. Now is the time to attack.
被他们逃走了，该进攻了
Not today.
今天休兵
You're all fools!
你们全是笨蛋
The Volturi might be gone.
机不可失啊
But they will never forgive
他们绝不会饶恕
what happened here.
这发生了什么
You have a beautiful family.
你有一个美丽的家庭
She's gonna be around for a long time, isn't she?
她还会陪我们很久，对吧？
A very long time.
长长久久
I'm glad she has you.
很高兴有你陪她
So should I start calling you "Dad"?
那我该开始叫你老爸了？
No.
不准
Hey.
女儿
Yeah. We're all gonna be together now.
对，我们都会在一起了
I wanna show you something.
我要给你看一样东西
What?
什么？
I'm Edward Cullen.
我是爱德华库伦
How did you do that?
妳怎么做到的？
Been practicing.
我练过
Now you know.
现在你明白了
Nobody's ever loved anybody as much as I love you.
没人像我爱你一样深爱一个人
There's one exception.
我是例外
Will you show me again?
再给我看一次好吗？
We've got a lotta time.
来日方长呢
Forever.
永远